Finding Aid for the Kitty Buhler Bradley Scripts PASC.0228
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kitty Buhler Bradley scripts
circa 1954-circa 1968
UCLA Library Special Collections
Buhler, Kitty
PASC.0228
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Kitty Buhler was a screen writer whose credits include the television series My Three Sons and The Untouchables. The collection includes 40-plus scripts related to Buhler's writing career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9946589583606533
Biography
Esther Dora Biolo (later Kitty Buhler and Esther Kitty Bradley) was born July 23, 1922 in New York City. She attended Manhattan Business College, Kansas Wesleyan University, and the University of California, Los Angeles. From 1949-1951 she worked for the United Press covering general news and the operation of B-29 activities in Okinawa during the Korean conflict. During this time she also wrote a daily column for Stars and Stripes called Dapers by Kit. She met WWII General Omar Bradley in 1950 (in Okinawa) and the two eventually married following the death of Bradley's first wife in 1965. She returned to Southern California in the mid-1950s and started writing for the entertainment industry. Among her credits are the episodic television series My Three Sons, The Untouchables and The 20th Century Fox Hour, and feature film China Doll, which starred Victor Mature and Li Li Hau.
During her career she also wrote human interest and non-fiction articles in national and international magazines, including Look. Her professional affiliations included the Writers Guild of America West, The Greater Los Angeles Press Club, and The National League of the American Pen Women, Inc. Buhler assisted General Bradley when he served as the technical advisor on the Academy Award winning film Patton. In 1981 President Reagan appointed her to the American Battle Monuments Commission. Kitty Buhler died February 3, 2004, in Rancho Mirage, CA at the age of 81.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 40-plus television scripts related to the career of writer Kitty Buhler. The writings include projects such as Bewitched, Bonanza, Dragnet, The Ray Milland Show, and My Three Sons among others. Additionally, there is one script for the film China Doll, which appears to be Buhler's only documented motion picture credit.
Organization and Arrangement
The scripts are arranged alphabetically by project title.
Television scripts.; Television writers -- Archives.; Buhler, Kitty--Archives.
- Baby Serenade, no date (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beachcomber (The), no date (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bewitched, no date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bonanza, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cara Williams Show (The), 1965 Jan 29 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Chaos, no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
- China Doll, no date (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 20th Century Fox Hour: City in Flames, 1956 Nov 12 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Crossroads, no date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Daniel Boone, no date (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Dateline Tokyo, no date (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dragnet, no date (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Dram of Love, A, no date (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Fast (The), no date (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Those Whiting Girls: Feminine Touch (The), 1957 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Globe Squatters (The), no date (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Hal Roach Rascals (The), no date (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Irene, no date (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Juvenile Delinquency, no date (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lady with a Badge, no date (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Hollywood Opening Night: Legal Affair, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Lineup, no date (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Marriage Counselor, no date (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 20th Century Fox Hour: Men in Her Life, 1957 Jan 18 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Mother Carey's Chickens, no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- My Three Sons, 1961 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- My Three Sons, 1963 Jun 11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- My Three Sons, 1964 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Password Okinawa, no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Petticoat Junction: Billie Jo's First Job, no date (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Please Don't Eat the Daises, Where Do You Hide An Elephant?, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Prince and Miss Bishop (The), no date (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Private Custody, no date (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Producer's Chair (The), no date (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ray Milland Show (The), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Ray Milland Show (The), no date (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Roommates, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Screen Credits, no date (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Temporary Insanity, 1955 Feb 8 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Tessa, 1956 Sep 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 20th Century Fox Hour: Threat to a Happy Ending (A), 1956 Aug (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Tightrope: Gangster's Daughter, 1960 Feb 16 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Untouchables (The): Come and Kill Me, 1960 Sep (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Up On the Hill, no date (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Valentine's Day: Cherry Blossoms in New York, 1964 July 30 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Vera Vague Show (The), no date (Box 5, Folder 2)
- World of Judge Barnaby (The), no date (Box 1, Folder 12)